# **Aakash Dixit**

aakash.dixit@outlook.com

+91 8588928763

Faridabad, Haryana, IN

LinkedIn

Over 8+ years of IT Industry experience as a DevOps Engineer, Clear Quest in Linux and containers (Docker, Kubernetes) environments. Knowledge of Ansible helps to automate repetitive tasks, quickly deploy critical applications, and proactively manage change. Set up the framework for clicks build and deployment on non-production environments.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Capgemini Engineering Pvt Ltd - Senior Consultant

May 2021 - current Gurgaon

- Designed and implemented appropriate environments for 9+ applications under one Virtualized Network Functions (VNF).
- Engineered suitable release management procedures and provided production support for different teams/projects.
- Ensured all the project documentation was created and updated, including design, planning, deployment, and upgrade documentation.
- Managing Cloud environments, automation, monitoring metrics, disaster recovery/backups, and capacity planning of VMs in VNF.
- Spearheaded 5+ junior engineers in the team to gain experience in Cloud technologies, processes, and best practices.
- Redesigned legacy applications for Cloud implementation with the team.
- Automated the provisioning of environments with Ansible and deployed environments using Kubernetes containers.
- Followed the Agile DevOps culture for deployment, testing, monitoring and upgrade of new features in the VNF.
- Troubleshoot system, application logs to debug the real cause behind the issue raised.

# Mobileum Technologies Private Limited - Lead Deployment Engineer

December 2020 - April 2021

Bangaore

- Deploy new logic by developing 2+ installation, deployment, and maintenance scripts.
- Worked on a team of 3 to achieve deployment of software through production and monitoring.
- Managed automation, auditing, and another tooling for security, compliance, and resource usage.
- Managing Git Repositories and relevant permissions including branching and tagging.

# Ericsson Global India Private Limited - Solution Integrator

January 2016 - December 2020

Gurgaon

- Researched and recommended 3 new technologies and emerging operational practices to the service managers.
- Collaborated with multiple solution architects, senior engineers, and the engineering manager to define release management processes.
- Developed 2 Linux scripts to reduce working man hours.
- Mentored 10+ junior engineers in gaining experience and assuming responsibilities.
- Managed the transition between project planning and application deployment.
- Ensured all the project documentation was created and updated, including design, development, and deployment documentation.
- Managed development of a robust Cloud platform sitting on Ericsson inhouse architecture.

## One97 Communications Private Limited - Sofware Engineer

February 2015 - January 2016

Noida

- Collaborated with and garnered feedback from product managers and analysts, and documented user data.
- Created Excel and MySQL query for stakeholders to help business products planners to create business plans to get released in the market.
- Built MySQL scripts to create business KPI reports for business teams.

## Mahindra Comviva - Support Engineer

April 2013 - December 2014

Gurgaon

- Collaborated with the development team, escalating issues as needed via ticketing system and prompt
- · communication.
- Documented all ticket resolutions, and drafted troubleshooting guides for the internal team with images,
- · descriptions, and strategies.
- Created and reorganized SQL queries and scripts for internal troubleshooting.
- Built MySQL scripts to fetch data for business reports.

#### **EDUCATION**

# C-DAC - PGDiploma in IT Infrastructure and System Security, IT Infrastructure

August 2012 - February 2013

# Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya -

Bachelor Of Engineering, Electronics and Communications

September 2008 - June 2012

### **SKILLS**

Kubernetes; Docker; Python; MySQL; AWS; RedHat OpenStack; Jupyter Notebook; Terraform, Ansible; Shell Scripting; Jira

### CERTIFICATIONS

- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- RedHat OpenStack (RHOS)
- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)